ILGWU. Carl Proper papers 5780/150
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- International Confederation of Free Trade Unions (IFCTU), 1983-1991 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  Executive Board minutes, November 20-22, 1991; statement on the Uruguay Round of multilateral trade negotiations, urging inclusion of minimum labor standards, adopted by Executive Board, November 19-21, 1986, and GATT newsletter outlining plans; minutes of several other agenda item of November 19-21 Executive Board meeting; IFCTU publications on trade union rights and survey of violations, 1983-84, 1984-85; on Asian labor, September-October 1984; March-April and May-June 1985; Free Labour World, noting 35th anniversary of IFCTU, 1984; draft report on child labor, with cover letter to all affiliates, June 10, 1985; statement on United Nations International Year of Peace, 1986; minutes of ICFTU Working Party on Peace, Security and Disarmament, Sept. 11-12, 1986
- International Labour Office, 1988-1992 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  Part of the International Labour Organisation, a United Nations agency. Questionnaire to ILG president Mazur from the ILO in preparation for the 1992 meeting re the footwear and leather industry, with summary of resolutions from previous meetings; resolutions of meetings on the clothing industry, 1986; letter to Mazur from ILO Washington branch director with article re failure of U.S. to meet U.N. financial obligations, 1988; newsletters, ILO Information, re aging, Eastern Europe, 1991; ILO Washington Focus, re need for labor standards for part-time workers, 1991; Worker Rights News, published by the International Labor Rights Education and Research Fund, February 1989; Publications Update, World Bank, April 1992
- Invest in America Working Group, 1991-1992 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  Coalition of organizations, chaired by the American Federation of State, County and Municipal Employees (AFSCME) and the U.S. Conference of Mayors, lobbying for a shift away from federal military spending in favor of domestic initiatives; list of members, description of organizational structure, activities
- Labor Research Association (2 folders), 1985-1994 (Box 10, Folder 14-15)
  Correspondence re dispute within ALF-CIO over alleged support by LRA for Communist-controlled World Federation of Trade Unions, 1986; newsletters
- Southern Finance Project: Financial Democracy Campaign, 1990-1991 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  Organization opposing savings-and-loan bailout, banking and insurance deregulation; Financial Democracy Campaign was a coalition of community organizations, churches, and unions, co-chaired by several labor organization leaders. Briefing papers: "Holes in the Safety Net: The NOLHGA Bid for Executive Life," re National Organization of Life and Health Guaranty Associations purchase of failed S&L, November 7, 1991; "Protecting the Public From Insurance Company Insolvencies: The Swiss Cheese Safety Net and How to Fix It," June 19, 1991; "What's the Guaranty? Insurer Insolvencies, the Public, and Guaranty Funds in the South," February 1990; fact sheets, legislative updates; Testimony of Marty Leary, Research Director, Southern Finance Project, before the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation, U.S. Senate, February 27, 1991; research prospectus, "Retirees at Risk: Pension Plan Exposure to Insurance Industry Insolvencies," with cove letter to ILGWU exec. asst. James Parrott, November 11, 1991; "Overview of the Impact of the Collapse of the Executive Life Insurance Company," prepared by AFL-CIO Employee Benefits Department, c. 1991; newspaper clippings
- Southern Poverty Law Center, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  Materials by the Klanswatch Project: "The Ku Klux Klan: A History of Violence and Racism," third edition, 1988; brochures; descriptive letter
- Southern Regional Council, 1986-1991 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  Report, "The Climate for Workers in the United States: A Study and Report by the Southern Labor Institute, a special project of the Southern Regional Council," August 29, 1986, with transcript of article by the Bureau of National Affairs summarizing findings; letter to ILG president Jay Mazur re report; newsletter, Southern Changes, re industrial recruitment (Saturn in Tennessee), racial issues
- Tri-State Economic Justice Network, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  Association of labor, community, and religious organizations. Draft proposal, "A Concept Proposal to Establish a Development Bank for the New York-New Jersey Metropolitan Region" with cover letter; article by director Stephen Strahs in City Limits, March 1991, promoting use of Port Authority resources for establishment of development bank
- D. Work in America Institute (Box 10, Folder 19a)
- Work in America Institute, 1991-1992 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  Board of Directors meetings minutes, November 20, 1991; updates on activities and services; printed Progress Report, 1990-92; correspondence with ILGWU officials
- Productivity Forum, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  Productivity Forum "New Roles for Unions" agenda, list of attendees, and presentations by United Auto Workers and Communications Workers of America, United Steelworkers of America, Energy and Chemical Workers Union local 800
- Publications, 1991-1992 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  Newsletters, including headliner, "ILGWU: A Model Union Role in Industrial Development Efforts"; press releases; brochures library and information service subject index; policy study, "New Roles for Managers, Part IV"
- Saturn Plant Visit, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  Correspondence inviting ILGWU president Mazur to tour of plant; 1992 Saturn annual report; presentation materials
- V. Labor-Management Committees Subseries (Box 11, Folder 4a)
- Labor-Management Committees, 1987-1990 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  Correspondence from ILGWU president Mazur to other officials; minutes of meetings leading up to the establishment of the Council for American Fashion as the umbrella organization of labor-management committees in the northeastern United States; speech by Mazur to NY Governor Cuomo's Labor-Management Conference, May 15, 1990, "Labor-Management Planning for a Revitalized Manufacturing Sector: The ILGWU Approach in the Apparel Industry"; Gov. Cuomo's State of the State message, January 4, 1989, hand-annotated by ILGWU exec. asst. James Parrott, with cover memo to president Mazur re highlights, creation of statewide labor-management committee; NYS Dept. of Labor newsletter, NY Works, with article about the newly established Office of Labor-Management Affairs, September 1988; hand-drawn schematic of organization of labor-management committees; handwritten notes of meetings
- A. Council for American Fashion (CAF) (Box 11, Folder 5a)
  A labor-management committee promoting economic development in the northeast; located at ILGWU headquarters, co- chaired by ILGWU president Jay Mazur and Eli Elias, president of the New York Skirt and Sportswear Association; Carl Proper was executive director. Called first the Women's and Children's Apparel Labor-Management Committee; then Fashion Industries Economic Development Council; name changed to Council for American Fashion as of October 26, 1989.
- Bylaws, Registration, Financial Records, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  Bylaws, charity registration forms, financial statements, handwritten notes
- Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service (FMCS): Grant Application (2 folders), 1987-1992 (Box 11, Folder 7-8)
  ILGWU grant request establishing a women's and children's apparel labor-management committee (CAF), May 1989; industry problem statement (by Carl Proper?); research paper, "Critical Factors in the Success of an Area Labor-Management Committee: A Comparative Evaluation," Robert W. Miller and Frederick A. Zeller, West Va. Univ. Institute of Industrial and Labor Relations; list of parties excluded from federal grant programs, Feb. 24, 1992; correspondence, handwritten notes; articles from union publication Justice (?) re establishment CAF and new GIDC Super Sewers training program
- Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service (FMCS): Grant Lobbying, 1989-1990 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  Correspondence (letters of support from Massachusetts governor Robert Casey, Massachusetts Sen. Edward Kennedy, Pennsylvania Sen. Arlen Specter, etc.) with members of Congress, Labor Secretary Elizabeth Dole, and FMCS to retain/restore funding for the CAF labor-management cooperation program
- Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service (FMCS): Grant Renewal, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  Grant renewal application: "Women's and Children's Apparel Labor Management Committee: Application for Continued Funding Submitted to the Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service," March 2, 1991; "Notes for Continuation Funding Application to FMCS"; letters of support; notification of award, March 20, 1991; action plan for 1991-92; memo to ILGWU president Mazur from CAF exec. dir. Carl Proper, noting cancellation of funding for FMCS for 1992 due to an unnamed union representative's having antagonized the chair of the Congressional funding committee (notes current CAF grant will not be affected), Dec. 9, 1991; newspaper clipping
- Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service (FMCS): Conference, 1990-1992 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  Letters to Council for American Fashion executive director Carl Proper re presentation on CAF at the FMCS Sixth National Labor-Management Conference, January-June 1992; outline of talk; letter from Bruce Herman, director of the Garment Industry Development Corporation (GIDC), offering to make presentation at FMCS conference, with description of GIDC, September 30, 1991; conference program, 1990
- Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service (FMCS): Midterm and Final Evaluations, 1990-1993 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  Letter from FMCS grants manager acknowledging receipt of quarterly reports for period ending June 30, 1990, noting lack of progress, suggesting that proposal be revised, August 15, 1990; memo re visit from federal grants manager to examine records, September 18, 1990; outline of proposal revisions, directional shifts for CAF with greater emphasis on demonstration projects rather than studies; letter to FMCS discussing changes in direction, Nov. 1990; memo re reorganizing CAF into project groups, April 11, 1991; list of steering committee and other committee meeting dates, FMCS report due dates, events, other grant due dates; 1991-92 itemized budget with note, "supporting material for Sept. 1992 FMCS budget revision"; midterm and final evaluations of CAF as required by the FMCS grant: "Preliminary Assessment of the Council for American Fashion: A Labor/Management Partnership for the Apparel Industry," March 1991, and "The Council of American Fashions after Three Years An Evaluation," May 1993, both by Norman Eiger, Professor of Labor Studies, Rutgers, State University of New Jersey; correspondence with FMSC director re request for grant extension, 1991-92; itemized budgets
- Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service (FMCS): Final Report & Audit, 1993 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  Correspondence, steering committee minutes, background material for audit and final evaluation, printed brochure by CAF, "High Fashion, High Tech, High Skill: Notes on the Future of the American Apparel Industry"
- Audit, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  Audit by Wolf & Schulman, CPA, for year ended December 31, 1992, and for the period Oct. 1, 1989 to Sept. 30, 1992; grant application, itemized budget information, memo
- Audit: Time Sheets (2 Folders), 1989-1993 (Box 12, Folder 1-2)
  Time sheets for exec. dir. Carl Proper accounting for major daily activities; and for secretaries; Carl Proper's pocket planner, 1990-91
- Personnel, 1991 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  Applications for project director; memos re budget for staff, May 7 and 17, 1991
- Quarterly Reports to Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service (FMCS): First Quarter (1989), 1989-1990 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  Includes budget change request, 13-page narrative description of project activities, newsletter, handwritten memo from Carl Proper, letter from FMCS noting progress
- Quarterly Reports to Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service (FMCS): Second Quarter (1990) (Box 12, Folder 5)
  Includes financial status report, 14-page narrative, Steering Committee minutes, Jan. 30, 1990
- Quarterly Reports to Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service (FMCS): Third Quarter (1990) (Box 12, Folder 6)
  Includes financial status report, 10-page narrative
- Quarterly Reports to Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service (FMCS): Fourth Quarter (1990) (Box 12, Folder 7)
  Description of Marketing/Technology study being conducted by Kurt Salmon Associates for the Garment Industry Development Corp., the CAF affiliated labor-management committee for NYC; financial status report
- Quarterly Reports to Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service (FMCS): Sixth Quarter (1991) (Box 12, Folder 9)
  Includes financial status report; 7-page narrative
- Quarterly Reports to Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service (FMCS): Seventh Quarter (1991), 1991-1992 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  Includes financial status report; 11-page narrative
- Quarterly Reports to Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service (FMCS): Eighth & Ninth Quarters (1991), 1991-1992 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  Narratives, financial status reports, correspondence
- Quarterly Reports to Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service (FMCS): Tenth & Eleventh Quarters (1992) (Box 12, Folder 12)
  Budget change request, Aug. 11, 1992, and related correspondence; financial status reports
- Quarterly Reports to Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service (FMCS): Twelfth Quarter (1993) (Box 12, Folder 13)
  Financial status report; memo
- Report to ILGWU General Executive Board, 1990-1991 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  Outline of structure and goals of CAF; Jay Mazur intro to report; overhead transparencies; handwritten notes; report to the GEB meeting of January 1991 by Carl Proper re accomplishments and near-term plans of Council for American Fashion and related labor-management committees; handwritten notes
- Report to ILGWU Organizing Staff, 1990-1991 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  The U.S. Women's Apparel Industry: Basic Characteristics and Organizing Potential; regional organizing plans; slide presentation on labor-management programs; presentation to ILGWU business agents and other staff by Carl Proper re Council for American Fashion, efforts of labor-management committees, relevance to union objectives in maintaining health of industry
- Financial Records, 1991-1992 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  Memo re audit required for closing out FMCS grant, Sept. 23, 1992; bills not part of grant; salary and fringe benefit costs
- Financial Record, 1989-1990 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  Invoices submitted to and paid by the ILGWU
- Financial Records: Fashion Exports and New York, 1992-1993 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  Invoices and memos in connection with Fashion Exports/New York expenses
- Annual Report, 1991 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  Report, distribution list
- Council for American Fashion, 1989 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  Called first the Women's and Children's Apparel Labor-Management Committee; then Fashion Industries Economic Development Council; name changed to Council for American Fashion as of October 26, 1989. Minutes, June 27, 1989; list of subcommittees and members as of Sept. 22; letter noting approval of FMCS grant
- Council for American Fashion, 1990 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  Report to the ILGWU General Executive Board, May 8, 1990; agenda, CAF Steering Committee, March 27, 1990; memo from ILGWU exec. ass. James Parrott to CAF director James Proper re follow-up on CAF meetings, May 17, 1990; FAM Board of Directors meeting outline of talking points, May 22, 1990; talk to Rutgers Conference on Women's Work (by Carl Proper?), May 22, 1990; memo to ILGWU president Mazur from exec. asst. James Parrott re frustrating meeting with ACTWU labor-management committee, with handwritten notes, May 23, 1990; memos to Mazur from Parrott re Leslie Fay and (TC)2, April 12, 1990; letter from Greater Blouse, Skirt & Undergarment Association to Mazur congratulating him on "swell" CAF January meeting, need for accurate public relations for Chinatown, February 7, 1990; press release, "Council for American Fashion to Modernize Apparel Manufacturing," March 22, 1990
- Council for American Fashion: First & Second Quarters (Jan.-June) (2 Folders), 1991 (Box 13, Folder 3-4)
  Annual Report; personal note from ILGWU president Mazur to Marvin [Feldman, president of FIT], urging that Prof. Irwin Kahn be allowed the time to continue contributing to CAF and GIDC rather than being forced back to the classroom, February 27, 1991; nomination by ILGWU president Mazur of Eli Elias, exec. dir. of the New York Skirt and Sportswear Association and co-chair with Mazur of CAF, to Crain's New York Business as Crain's All-Star for 1990, related material; memo to ILGWU exec. asst. James Parrott from CAF dir. Carl Proper re finding funds in current budget for export expert, February 13, 1991; ten-page notes for continuation budget, CAF goals, for submission to Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service (FMCS), with note from Proper to Parrott, related memos; memo from Proper to Parrot re work situation on Long Island: homework, Chinese and Hispanic workforce, practice of Chinese-owned manufacturers moving from Chinatown to Long Island to avoid unionization, discusses specific shops, strategy, May 23, 1991; memos re export program, Hong Kong trade show; profile of Atlantic Apparel Contractors Association in Lehigh Valley Business Digest, February 1991; draft of minutes of New Jersey Apparel Labor-Management Committee, January 31, 1991, with cover note from Carl Proper to James Parrott; report of survey of Long Island, April May 1991, by Prof. Phil Kelman, Manufacturing Management Department, Fashion Institute of Technology; "A Preliminary Assessment of the Council for American Fashion: A Labor-Management Partnership for the Apparel Industry," by Norman Eiger, professor of labor studies, Rutgers University, March 1, 1991; summary of apparel industry labor-management activities, April 25, 1991; list of CAF/GIDC exporters and potential exporters, newspaper clippings, handwritten notes
- Council for American Fashion: Third & Fourth Quarter (July-December), 1991 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  Correspondence between ILGWU president Mazur and Garment Industry Development Association (GIDC) re funding requests; description of GIDC sent to FMCS; memo re ergonomics conference; application by GIDC to the NYS Dept. of Economic Development, October 1, 1991; notes re conversation with representative of Japanese retailer Takishimaya; newspaper clippings
- Council for American Fashion (2 folders), 1992 (Box 13, Folder 6-7)
  Agenda for Sept. 10 CAF Steering Committee meeting; draft and final text of remarks by ILG president Mazur; agendas for Planning Committee meetings, January 27 and February 19, 1992 (ILGWU-CAF-GIDC-FIT); correspondence with NYC economic development officials re promotion of garment industry, including "A Proposal to Promote New York's Fashion Industry," submitted by ILGWU, Jay Mazur, President, August 1990; outline of talk to FMCS, Sept. 15, 1992 (probably Mazur); correspondence re site visit by FMCS, July-August 1992; memo re meeting with NYS Assembly leadership re garment industry economic development needs, Sept, 10, 1992; CAF planning meeting agendas or notes, May 15, July 6, August 20, Oct. 13, 1992; notes on KSA/GIDC meeting (Kurt Salmon Associates/Garment Industry Development Corp), Aug. 18, 1992; research paper, "The Role of Big Buyers in Global Commodity Chains: How U.S. Retail Networks Affect Overseas Production Patterns," Gary Gereffi, Duke University, presented at the Political Economy of the World-System Conference, April 16-18, 1992; fact sheet, "Modular Manufacturing Pay Systems: Alternatives to Piecework," Cornell ILR School, Sept. 9, 1992; article reprint, "Modular's True Colors," from trade journal Bobbin, July 1992, with note to ILG James Parrott from Carl Proper; memo from Proper to Parrott endorsing collaborating with Alfred Dunner despite being non-union manufacturer, July 23; draft proposal, Central Atlantic Manufacturing Technology Center, New Jersey Institute of Technology (NJIT) Regional MTC Program, April 7, 1992; list of contractors working for top designers, Dec. 6, 1991; letter from Carl Proper as project director of Fashion Exports/New York to NJIT re developing trade with Newly Independent States (former Soviet Union), Aug, 21; list of services that CAF and GIDC could provide to manufacturers (productivity assessments, worker skills upgrading, short-cycle manufacturing development), May 30, 1992; memo re phone conversation with manufacturer requesting modular training; GIDC activity report, May-June, 1992; summary of export grant, description of CAF and Fashion Exports/New York program objectives; minutes of Aug. 13 CAF eastern Pennsylvania committee planning session; text of presentation for ILGWU New York-New Jersey Staff Conference on Labor-Management and Industry Development Programs, Gail E. Meyer, with cover note to exec. asst. James Parrott, June 3; New Jersey Labor-Management Committee Steering Committee Minutes, Aug. 5, 1992; Report of the ILGWU TARP Project, submitted by Barbara Cameron, research coordinator, September 1991 (discusses homework as a substitute for modernizing, training, and technology); letter appointing Prof. Philip Kelman as part-time Project Director for the Long-Island Apparel Labor-Management Committee, July 17, 1991; "Report of Survey: Boston Area Sewing Contractors, Week of January 14, 1991," submitted by Prof. Kelman; paper and invoice by Dr. Ellen Rosen, "Assessing the Skills Base Among Apparel Workers in the Long Island Labor Market Area (Nassau-Suffolk Counties), prepared for the Council for American Fashion," Sept. 1992; handwritten notes
- B. CAF Committees (Box 13, Folder 6a)
- Marketing Committee, 1989 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  Strategic report of marketing committee, established to provide marketing expertise to garment industry manufacturers, particularly for exporting; agendas; handwritten notes
- Public Relations Committee, 1989-1993 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  Proposed public relations activities to promote CAF and positive garment industry image; agendas and minutes; handwritten notes, newspaper clippings, press releases
- Public Relations Committee: Brochure, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  Drafts of manuscript, memos re text for promotional brochure, part of a PR campaign aimed at national and state elected officials and opinion leaders
- Steering Committee, 1989-1991 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  Minutes, 11/8/89-9/25/91; "Role of Steering Committee and relation to various local committees such as GIDC, NTAP, Lehigh Valley"; CAF mailing list, 4/23/90; contract and reports to NYS Department of Labor with overview of CAF, 1991
- Meeting: 6/27/1989 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  Agenda, report by Mazur (?), handwritten notes
- Meeting: 9/15/1989 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  Minutes, agenda, opening remarks, handwritten notes, committee membership
- Meeting: 10/26/1989 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  Minutes, agenda, letters of invitation, reports of labor task force, technology, marketing, public relations committees, list of committee membership
- Meeting: 1/30/1990 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  Minutes, agenda, handwritten notes, reports of technology, public relations, labor force committees, summary of Needle Trades Action Project (Boston, MA, labor-management committee); letters of invitation from ILGWU president Mazur; memo from ILGWU president Mazur re expansion of committee membership, list of committee membership, description of GIDC market and technology study, materials re TC2 educational program and plant tour
- Meeting: 3/27/1990 (Box 13, Folder 16)